# Yash Nagar

+91 7791895631 **in** LinkedIn **()** Github **M** Gmail

# **Objective**

Ambitious Java Developer versed in following established procedures and working under little or no supervision. Offering technical expertise in programming analysis, application analysis and design. Excellent team player with in-depth knowledge of development tools and languages.

## **Education**

## **College of Engineering and Technology**

Bachelors of Technology In ECE

2015 - 2019 | Bikaner, Rajasthan

## **Experience**

## **Alpha Numero**

Java Developer

. . . . . .

- Managed Confluence documentation and Bit Rock Installer for streamlined deployment.
- Configured High Availability on PostgreSQL and conducted database metadata analysis.
- Installed and integrated Dynamo DB, MongoDB, and Spark Database for efficient data management.
- Implemented front-end changes on Product UI and compared metadata across databases.
- Automated Azure Machine and Services, reducing deployment time.
- Installed Raven DB, developed backend/frontend, and managed tasks on JIRA.

#### Seed Infotech Ltd.

Jul 2022 - Mar 2023 | Pune, Maharashtra

Apr 2023 - present | Ahmedabad, Gujrat

Full Stack Java Developer, Intern

- Six-month Full Stack Development training
- Covered Java technologies: J2SE/J2EE, JSP & Servlets, Spring, Spring Boot, Hibernate
- Proficiency gained in Oracle SQL Database, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap
- Utilized Maven for project management and Tomcat Server for deployment

#### Diloeya Plaster

Oct 2019 - May 2022 | Bikaner, Rajasthan

Technical In-Charge

- Provides work direction and participates in the construction, installation, operation, maintenance, and inspection.

#### **Projects**

#### **Portfolio Website**

- Dynamic web app using Java (J2EE, Servlets, JSP) with CSS, JavaScript, and Bootstrap.
- J2EE Architecture: Utilized J2EE architecture for scalability.
- Layered Structure: Implemented Controller, Service, Dao, Model layers for efficiency.
- Secure Admin Panel: Designed secure admin panel with user authentication and session management.
- Database Integration: Integrated MySQL for seamless data storage and retrieval.

#### **Login Logout**

- **Dynamic Web App**: Utilized JSP, Servlet, J2EE, HTML, and CSS for dynamic web application with layered structure comprising Controller, Service, Dao, and Validation layers for efficiency.
- **Secure Admin Panel**: Implemented session management for secure admin panel.
- **Database Integration**: Utilized MySQL for seamless data management within the application.

#### Skills

Frontend (HTML, CSS, Bootstrap) • Programming Language (Java (J2SE, J2EE)) • DataBase Access (JPA, Hibernate, JDBC)

• Web FrameWorks (Spring Framework(SpringBoot, MVC)) • Database (SQL Database(PostgreSQL,MySQL),

NoSQL(MongoDB)) • Server (XAMPP, Apache Tomcat) • IDE (Eclipse, VS Code) • Build Tool (Maven) • Server (Tomcat, XAMPP) • Java Web Development (Servlets and JSP) • Environment (Linux, Ubuntu, Windows)

# **Certificates**

# Full Stack Java Developer

SEED Infotech Pune

## Others Skills

• Swift Learner

- Adaptability
- Teamwork

Learn to New Skills